# Hossein Kamyab August 20, 1996

Personal Email: Official Email: LinkedIn: hosseinkamyab
hosseinkamyab@modarec.ac.ir Phone: +98-917-690-5977

Hossein Kamyab is a teacher and computational designer with a strong interest in structural design and its contribution to sustainable architecture. He holds a Master of Architecture degree from Tarbiat Modares University of Tehran. For his master's thesis, he conducted in-depth research on the structural reconstruction of muqarnas—an ornamental element of Islamic architecture—using a structural design methodology known as graphic statics. This research focused on converting previously ornamental elements into structurally efficient ones. It aimed to regenerate these elements for efficient material use and align them with modern sustainability standards while preserving their historical significance. Supervised by Dr. Damon Bolhassani from the City College of New York, this research was published and presented at the IASS 2022 conference.

Hossein's interest in complex geometries and their real-world applications led him to study architecture for his bachelor's degree, an interest he further pursued during his master's by exploring computational design methods. For his Ph.D., he plans to advance his research by investigating the application of machine learning and computer vision in architecture and structural design to contribute to a more sustainable future. Since 2019, Hossein has shared his passion for architecture, structures, and sustainability as a registered teacher in vocational high schools under the Iranian Ministry of Education.

Education				
2020 - 2022	Tarbiat Modares University (TMU)  Master of Architecture (M.Arch.)	A:18.95/20 or 4.0/4.0	Tehran,Iran	
2015 - 2019	Shahid Rajae Teacher Training University (SRTTU)		Tehran,Iran	
	Bachelor of Architecture (B,Arch) GP/	A:17.63 / 20 or 3.64/ 4.0		
2011 - 2015	Ebnesina Magnet High school Diploma in Mathematics & Physics	'A: 17.36 / 20	Shiraz ,Iran	
Academic Experience				
2023- 2024	Allameh khafri Vocational High school		Shiraz ,Iran	
	Architectural Design, Architectural drafting			
2022- 2023	Kharazmi Vocational High school Architectural drafting, AutoCAD for architects, construction		Shiraz ,lran	
2021- 2022	Farahbakhsh Vocational High school  Architectural Design , Architectural drafting, AutoCAD for architects, construction Details		Tehran,Iran	
2019- 2021	Allameh khafri Vocational High school		Shiraz ,Iran	
	Architectural Design ,structural drafting, Building Construction & Material, Reinforced Concrete & Steel Structures			

## **Publications**

- H. Kamyab, M. Yeganeh, and M. bolhassani, "Structural muqarnas: Reconstructing muqarnas using graphic statics", IASS/APCS 2022
- Z. Shirzadnia ,H. Kamyab and A.Zarkesh "Assessment of timber gridshells in the study of new structures," Third National Conference on New Researches in Engineering and Applied Sciences, 2021, Iran, Borujerd.

A.Farajolahi ,A.Vaezi, H.Kamyab et al , "Industrial Architecture Of Iran",farajolahi publication, 2021,ISBN: 978-622-96814-8-0

Events and Workshops		
Playing Models : Artificial Intelligence, Architecture, Storytelling will take <u>The 3rd Edition of Playing Models   hybrid conference  ETH Zürich</u>		
Bio-Integrated Modular Free Form Structures Intelligent Design <u>DigitalFUTURES   Youtube Stream  Online</u>	2023	
Instructors: Selda Pourali / Ahmed Sattar / Behnaz Khaksar / Mentor: Mahdi Fard		
Presentation of published paper  IASS conference   hybrid conference   Beijing, China  Presenting the paper called "structural muqarnas: reconstruction of muqarnas using graphic statics	2022	
Form-Finding Staircases With COMPAS CEM	2021	
Acadia   Structural design   Online Workshop Instructors: Rafael Pastrana , Isabel Moreira de Oliveira , Patrick Ole Ohlbrock, Pierluigi D'Acunto		
PRINT in PRINT: Nesting Robotic 3D Printing	2021	
<u>Digital Futures   Fabrication   Online Workshop</u> Instructors: Negar Kalantar, AliReza Borhani, Mehdi Farahbakhsh		
Awards and Honors		
Addimsion offer with a 20,000\$ scholarship for M.S in architecture at University of Pennsylvania's Weitzman School of Design	2024	
Addimsion offer with a 17,000\$ scholarship for M.S in architecture at City College of New York's Spitzer School of Architecture	2024	
Master Graduation with A grade in the third university of Iran	2022	
Ranked 32 <sup>th</sup> / 6000 - Iranian University Entrance Exam for Master's Degree	2020	
3% within 222500 - Iranian University Entrance Exam for Bachelor's Degree top	2014	

## digital Skills

Programming languages: Python

Neural Networks: Artificial Neural Networks (ANNs),

Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs)

Libraries: PyTorch, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Scikit-Learn, OpenCV

Modeling: Rhino & Grasshopper, Revit, Sketch up, AutoCAD

Rhino & GHPlugin: HAL Robotics Framework, PolyFrame, CEM, Karamba, Octopus,

Ladybug (butterfly), Eddy3D, RhinoVAULT

Graphic Design Tools: InDesign, Photoshop, Illustrator

## References

#### Dr. Damon Bolhassani

#### **Assistant Professor**

Spitzer School of Architecture, The City College of New York 141 Convent Avenue, New York, New York, 10031

Email: mbolhassani@ccny.cuny.edu

## Dr. Mansour Yeganeh

### Associate Professor

Department of Architecture, Architectural Design, Modeling, and Fabrication lab, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran

Email: yeganeh@modares.ac.ir

#### Dr. Mehdi Ghiai

#### **Assistant Professor**

University of Louisiana at Lafayette, 104 E University Ave, Lafayette, LA 70504, USA

Email: mohammad-mehdi.ghiai@louisiana.edu